한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
재배포 허용. 수정은 제작자와 협의 하에
♪ Love is a madness
Love is a madness
♪ I can't get away
I can't get away
♪ It hurts me to love you
너 이새끼!
It hurts me to love you
Hey!
♪ And it hurts me to stay
And it hurts me to stay
♪ This sweet sadness
This sweet sadness
♪ Is this all I get?
Is this all I get?
너 이새끼 딱 걸렸어
You messed with
the wrong guy.
비켜!
Get off me.
진짜로, 비키라고!
No... move, man!
♪ Well, if I can't make you
love me ♪
Well, if I can't make you
love me
♪ And if I can't
make you pretend ♪
And if I can't
make you pretend
♪ I know I can't make you
want me, baby ♪
I know I can't make you
want me, baby
♪ Then there's nothing else
to recommend ♪
Then there's nothing else
to recommend
♪ I guess it has to end.
I guess it has to end.
913 빌딩의 저주와
The curse of building 913.
에버렛 해링턴 웬트워스라니
And Everett Harrington Wentworth.
도시괴담같은걸 믿지는 않지만
이번엔 믿어야겠는걸요
I never believe urban legends,
but this one I'm buying.
이 피해자는 1929년 E. 웬트워스가
이 건물 펜트하우스에서
투신 자살을 한 이후로 나타난
Our vic is the 37th bizarre death
connected to this address since
벌써 37번째 기괴한 사망자예요
Wentworth himself jumped
from the penthouse in 1929.
풍문에는 이 빌딩이 그 날 이후로
저주를 받았다고들 하고 있지
They say the building was
cursed on that very day.
웬트워스는 경기공황으로
모든 재산을 잃고 나서
Wentworth lost all his money
in the crash of the market.
정신 분열이 왔고,
결국 자살을 하게 되었지
Distraught,
he leapt to his death.
His beloved girlfriend,
Wilma Ashton...
쌔끈한 금발녀였던
그의 여자친구 윌마 애쉬턴은
웬트워스의 자살을 목격하게 되었고
a stunning blonde...
watched his fatal leap,
덩달아 자살을 해버렸어
then killed herself.
윌마는 피바다가 된 욕조에서
죽어있는 상태로 처음 발견되었지
She was found lying in a
pool of her own blood.
많은 사람들이 아직도 그 층에
유령이 배회하고 있다고 믿고 있고
Many believe their
ghosts roam the floors.
또 뭐 불가사의한 일이라던지
아니면 위층에서 뭔가 발견된 건 없었나?
Anything paranormal,
or otherwise, upstairs?
두 명 정도를 풀어서
예쁜 금발녀 피해자가 있나
I had a couple unis look around
조사해봤는데
수확은 없었죠
for a beautiful blonde,
but no luck.
여기 펜트하우스 아파트는
The penthouse apartment is used
낮 시간에는 귀신의 집 체험장소로,
as a haunted tourist
attraction during the day,
밤에는 클럽으로 사용되고 있어요
and a club at night.
It closes around 2:00 a.m.,
새벽 2시쯤에 영업이 끝나고,
근무자가 문을 걸어잠그는 건
새벽 3시~3시반 사이라 해요
employees finish locking
up about 3:00, 3:30.
그나저나 시드 박사님,
언제부터 이런 이상한 현장에 직접 나오셨나요?
Hey, Sid, how come they
only ever call you out
상부에서 시킨 건가요?
to the really strange ones?
위에서 시킨 게 아닐세
They... didn't call me.
이 사건은 평생 잊지 못할 사건이라서.
Uh, this is one
I was not going to miss.
지상에 있던 목격자의 말로는
피해자가 위에서부터 떨어졌다고 해요
Witnesses on the ground report
that our vic fell from above.
비명 소리가 들려서 위를 올려봤더니
사람이 거꾸러져 떨어지고 있었다고 하고요
The heard a roar, looked
up, saw him mid-plunge.
이 택시의 운전자는 커피를 마시러 가느라
여기에 차를 대 놨다고 해요
This cabdriver parked here
to get a cup of coffee.
덕분에 떨어지는 순간을
목격하지는 못했지만요
Luckily, he missed
all the excitement.
피해자가 정확히 몇 층에서
떨어졌는지는 알 수 없는가?
No idea where exactly our
victim was when he fell?
아뇨, 하지만 건물 내부와 외부 인근의
No, but I'm collecting surveillance
from all the cameras in the vicinity
모든 감시카메라의 영상을 수집하고 있어요
and inside the building.
1920년대풍 복장에
1920s attire.
가죽 가면이라..
A leather mask.
잠시 헌사를 하자면,
웬트워스는 당대 최고의 호화로운 갑부였다네
In tribute, uh, Wentworth
was the Gatsby of his time.
그는 가죽 제품들을 만들어
부를 쌓았지.
Uh, made his fortune
in leather goods.
흉터는 그에게 생겼던 질병 때문이었지
He was scarred
from a disease.
태양에 대한 알레르기 반응이었을 거야
Allergy to the sun, I believe.
그 흉터를 가리려고 일부러
가죽으로 만든 복잡한 디자인의
Covered his face with
intricately-designed
마스크를 쓰고 다녔지
leather masks.
그럼 이 피해자는
웬트워스의 자살 이야기에 매혹되어
So our victim was fascinated
with Wentworth's story
and decided to commit suicide
그가 했던 자살과 똑같은 방법으로
the exact same way?
자살을 하기로 마음먹고
뛰어내렸다는건가요?
아니면 복고풍 파티에서
술을 잔뜩 먹고
Or, he was drunk
at the steam punk party,
잠깐 바깥 바람을 쐬려고 나왔다가
decided he needed
some fresh air,
실수로 떨어진 것일수도 있겠죠?
자살이 아니라?
woops, accident, not a suicide?
자살이나 사고사에 대해서는
벌써 배제가 가능할 것 같군
I've already eliminated
both those options.
이건 살인 사건이야
It's murder.
경동맥의 열상이 보이고,
Laceration of the carotid artery.
유리나 금속류가 튀어나온 것이
없는 걸로 봐서는
And, no protruding glass or metal
외부에서 충격을
가한 것으로 보이네
to suggest it happened
from the impact.
플랙, 금발 여자를 찾는 수색
And I wouldn't give up
your search for that
계속 해줘야겠군.
beautiful blonde, Flack.
립스틱 키스 자국이라.
Lipstick kiss.
키스의 주인공은
멀쩡히 살아있을 가능성이 높고,
My guess is she's alive and well.
살인을 저지른 자일 수도 있다네
And could be our killer.
한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
CSI:NY S09E13
Nine Thirteen
Original Air Date : 2013. 01. 18.
♪ Out here in the fields
Out here in the fields
♪ I fight for my meals
I fight for my meals
♪ I get my back into my living
I get my back into my living
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
재배포 허용, 무단수정 금지
차에 부딪히면서 난 외상이
Well, uh, blunt force
trauma resulting
두개골에 긴 틈을
낼 정도의 충격을 주었고,
in a fissure fracture of the skull,
신체의 다른 모든 뼈에도
골절상을 입혔을 거야
and possibly the fracture of
every other bone in his body.
피해자가 날카로운 흉기에 찔린 다음에
바깥으로 밀려 떨어져버렸다는 증거도 있나요?
Is there any evidence that our killer
pushed him after he stabbed him?
글쎄, 상황을 놓고 보면
Well, with the victim
in this condition,
몸싸움이 있었을 거라고는
생각하기 힘들어
it'll be difficult to tell if there
was any kind of a... struggle.
왜죠?
What? What is it?
이 얼굴을 봐
Well, look at his face.
몸싸움을 벌이다가 떨어진
사람의 얼굴이 아니잖아
He doesn't look like
he fought the fall.
피해자는 날카로운 것에 찔린 다음에
방향 감각을 잃었을 것이고,
He could've been disoriented
as a result of the stabbing,
정신을 잃고 방황하다가
혼자서 떨어져버린 것이지
lost consciousness,
then, he just fell.
그 모든 걸 그냥
보기만 하셔도 알 수 있다고요?
You can tell all that
by just looking at him?
사실 과학적 연구 근거에
기반한 가설은 아니지만
Well, it's not based on any
published scientific research,
내가 오랫동안 부검대에 오른
피해자의 시신들을
just something over the years
that I've learned to see
조사하면서 얻은
직감에 따른 것이지
in the victims that have
been on my autopsy table.
이걸 보면 에블린 맥해일이 생각나
피해자는 당시 23세밖에 되지 않았지
Reminds me of Evelyn McHale.
She was only 23 years old.
1947년에 에블린은 추락으로 사망했지
In 1947,
she jumped to her death
엠파이어 스테이트 빌딩
전망대에서 떨어진 에블린은
from the observation deck of
the Empire State Building.
리무진 천장을 박살내버렸지
Landed on top of a limousine.
사건 현장에서 발견된 피해자는
손에 진주목걸이를 꼭 움켜쥐고 있었지
She was clutching her pearl
necklace when they found her.
아, 그 피해자가 라이프 매거진에 있는
유명한 사진의 주인공인가요?
Oh, is that that famous picture
from Life magazine?
그럼. 그들은 그 사건을 더러
"가장 아름다운 자살 사건"이라고 부르지
Yes, uh, they called it
"the most beautiful suicide"
사진 속의 피해자는
너무도 평온해보였어
In the photo, she
looked so peaceful.
린지, 자네 괜찮나?
Lindsay, are you okay?
왜요?
Why?
약간 상태가 안 좋아보이는데 말이야
You just look a little piqued.
- 아뇨, 전 괜찮아요
- 흠
- No, I'm fine.
- Hm.
피해자에 대한 정보를 입수했어요
I got a little, uh, info on our vic.
피해자는 에버렛 웬트워스처럼 갖춰입고
관광객이나 클럽 방문객들과
He dresses as Everett Wentworth and
takes pictures with the tourists
사진을 같이 찍어주는 사람이었어요
and the club patrons.
미스터리 하우스에 놀러와요!
Anybody want to come in?
Anybody?
여러분?
Anybody? You guys?
한 번 구경해 보셔요
Hey, come on in.
안녕하세요?
How are you guys doing?
준비되셨나요?
Ready?
좋아요, 고마워요
Great, thank you.
안녕하세요!
Hey, hey, hey.
Hi.
저랑 사진 한 장 찍어요.
Take a pic with me.
한 장만 더요.
준비되셨나요?
Hey, one more.
Ready?
그렇다면 피해자의 뺨에 립스틱 자국이
왜 생겼는지 설명할 수 있겠네요
Well, that could explain
the lipstick on his cheek.
이름은 뭐래요?
He got a name?
그건 좀 난제가 될 것 같아
That seems to be the hard part.
안내데스크에 있던 사람들은
피해자의 이름이 제이슨이라는 것만 알아
성씨는 모르고
Guys at the security desk
know him as Jason... just Jason...
그래서 그 사람들이
so they sent me upstairs
피해자가 일했던 미스터리 하우스 겸
나이트클럽에 날 올려보내줬는데
to the folks who run the
tours and nightclub,
거기 있던 사람들은 피해자의 이름을
제이크로 알고 있더군, 역시 성씨는 모르고
and they know him
as Jake, no last name.
그리고 10분 전까지는
And, until ten minutes ago,
모두가 피해자를
건물 근무자로 알고 있었다고 해
everybody thought he
worked for the building.
누구 말이 맞는지도 모르니
아무 의미도 없는 셈이지
So, we got nothing.
피해자에 대한 서류상의 정보며,
인적 사항, 신분증 등
We got no paperwork,
no background info, no permit.
신원에 대한 아무 정보도 없어
No identity.
그러니 이 에버렛 웬트워스 묘사꾼이
신원미상자라는 말이네요
So our Everett Wentworth
is a John Doe.
♪
♪ I ran from the tide
I ran from the tide
♪ Won't let you hide,
won't let you hide ♪
Won't let you hide,
won't let you hide
♪ I drop beats
from this processed meat ♪
I drop beats
from this processed meat
♪ For a conversation,
a meditation and ♪
For a conversation,
a meditation and
♪ I cut waves
like some unborn sage ♪
I cut waves
like some unborn sage
♪ Just like terrorists
on a day of rest singing ♪
Just like terrorists
on a day of rest singing
♪ I ran from the tide
I ran from the tide
♪ Won't let you hide,
won't let you hide ♪
Won't let you hide,
won't let you hide
♪ I break bones
stealing mobile phones ♪
I break bones
stealing mobile phones
♪ And I'm cuttin' deals
for these homeless meals ♪
And I'm cuttin' deals
for these homeless meals
♪ Making idle threats
using Chinese burns ♪
Making idle threats
using Chinese burns
♪ As you load my head with
the Grateful Dead singing ♪
As you load my head with
the Grateful Dead singing
♪ I ran from the tide
I ran from the tide
♪ Won't let you hide,
won't let you hide. ♪
Won't let you hide,
won't let you hide.
♪
시드 박사님이 보내준
열 손가락 지문에서
혹시 뭐 나온 것 없는가?
Anything on the prints
from Sid's ten card, Adam?
AFIS에 검색되는 건 없었어요
No hits in AFIS.
피해자는 여전히 신원미상이예요
The vic is still a John Doe.
이게 다 뭔가?
What's all this?
아, 이건 피해자가 입고 있던
자켓의 숨겨진 주머니에 들어있던
물건이예요
Ah, this stuff was found inside
the hidden pocket
on the vic's jacket.
피해자가 소매치기범이었군
Our vic was a pickpocket.
루저놈같으니
Loser.
아, 죄송합니다
부적절한 발언이었네요
Look, I-I-I I'm sorry,
that's inappropriate
제가 직업상 피해자에 대해
주관적 의견을 가져서는 안되는데 말이죠
and unprofessional; I'm not
supposed to have an opinion,
그런데 이 사람은 길거리에서
but, that guy was out
there taking pictures
아무 죄 없는 관광객들하고
사진을 찍어주는 척 하면서
with tourists, innocent tourists,
while he was stealing from them.
물건들을 슬쩍
훔쳐버렸다는 것 아니예요
사진 같이 찍어요
Pictures, pictures.
사진 같이 찍을래요?
You two want to take a pic?
-그래요
-그러죠
Yeah.
All right.
준비됐나요?
Ready?
하나, 둘, 셋!
Good? One, two, three.
고마워요, 다음에 또 봐요
Thank you.
See you, guys.
- 잘 가요
- 고마워요.
- Bye.
- Thanks.
지갑, 시계, 보석, 핸드폰 등등
Wallets, watches,
jewelry, phones.
루저놈 맞죠?
Loser, okay?
그리고 이걸 다 훔치고도
뻔뻔하게 계속 훔치고 있었잖아요
And he was getting away with it.
아닐 수도 있지
Or maybe not.
소매치기를 한 것 때문에
살해를 당한 것일 수도 있지
Maybe that's what
got him killed, Adam.
이 핸드폰 전원 모두 켜보고
원래 주인들이 누군가 찾아보고
Turn on all these phones,
track them to their owners.
호텔에 등록된 손님들의 정보들과
교차 조사해봐
Cross-reference any info you get
with registered guests in hotels.
보석류나 시계들은
일련번호가 있는가 찾아보고
See if any of the jewelry or
watches have serial numbers.
지갑에서는 신원을 알아보도록 하게
Look for I.D.'s in the wallets.
혹시 도난 신고가 되어있나 찾아보고,
Check to see if anything
was reported stolen.
지금으로서는, 이 도난품들의
주인들을 용의자라고 의심할 수밖에 없어
As of right now, every one
of these people is a suspect.
방금 소리 울린 이 전화기부터
조사해보게
And start with whoever
owns this phone.
도난품 주인들의 이름과 주소들을
빨리 알아낼 수 있도록 하게
I want a name and address
as soon as possible.
훔친 놈이 네놈인 줄 다 알아
두고봐라 내가 너 찾아낼꺼야
제 아들 셔츠를 가지러 왔어요
I'm here to pick up
shirts for my son.
조 댄빌이라는 이름으로
되어있을 거예요
It's under Jo Danville.
감사합니다
Thank you.
그건 너무 색이 밝은데요
Those are a little bright.
무슨 인간 신호등이라도 하시게요?
Are you trying to stop traffic?
맞는 말씀이네요,
그냥 평범한 걸로 골라야겠어요
You're right, I should just
go with something safe.
실제로 매 보기도 전에
그런 말을 하시면 안되죠
Well, you should
always try it on first.
눈동자 색깔과
잘 어울리나 확인해보세요
Make sure it looks
good with your eyes.
왜 절 계속 쫓아오고 있는거죠?
Why are you following me?
그런 거 아니거든요
Uh, I'm not following you.
15분 전에 커피숍에 있던거 다 봤어요
You were at the coffee shop
15 minutes ago.
허브 티를 시켜놓고는 마시지도 않았죠
You ordered herbal tea,
completely gave you away.
그거보다 15분 더 전에는
15 minutes before that,
우리집 바로 앞에 있는
버스정류장에서도 당신을 봤었죠
you were at a bus stop right
in front of my apartment.
우연의 일치랄까요?
Um, pleasant coincidence?
아니지, 당신 이름이 뭐죠?
No.
What's your name?
그랜트요,
그랜트 홀리스턴이요
Grant.
Grant Holliston.
내 또래 다른 여자들이라면
I suppose any other woman my age
매력적인 연하남이
자기한테 왜 관심을 가질까 하고
would be flattered,
assuming that she's got
the attention of a very
attractive younger man.
사탕발림에 넘어가겠지만
저는 그런 여자들과는 달리
똑똑한 여자거든요
But I'm a little
bit smarter than that.
기억해둬요 나는 연방 법원 집행관 앞에서
국가에의 봉사를 맹세한
You should know that I am
a first-grade detective,
전직 FBI 요원이자
현직 1급 형사예요
a sworn federal marshal,
former FBI agent,
그래서 저는 관찰력이 매우 뛰어난 사람이고,
지금 이 상황에 의심을 갖지 않을 수 없어요
which makes me highly suspicious
and acutely observant.
그러니 좋게 물어볼 때 대답해요
So, once again,
you want to tell me why
왜 날 미행하고 있죠?
you're following me?
뭐라고 말씀드려야 할 지 모르겠네요
Um... I'm not sure what to say.
저는 총도 갖고 있거든요?
I'm carrying a gun.
알겠어요
All right.
조용히 대화할 수 있는 장소에서
말씀드리도록 하죠
I'll tell you if we can
go someplace quiet.
하지만 대중에
노출되는 곳이어야 해요
But public.
그리고 무슨 일이 있어도
절 쏘지 않겠다고 약속해줘요
And you promise
not to shoot me.
좋아요
Deal.
피해자는 체내 모든 뼈에
골절을 입은 모양이네요
Looks like our vic fractured
every bone in his body.
그리고, 음...
Ah. Uh...
흉부와 골반부에 입은 부상을 보면
Thoracic and pelvic injuries
suggest that our victim fell
우리 피해자는 18미터 이상,
30미터 이하의 거리에서 떨어진 것으로 보여
from a distance of more than
18 meters, but less than 30.
거리를 보면 건물의 6층~10층
That's somewhere between
the sixth and tenth
정도 높이가 되겠군요
floors of the building.
피해자는 낙하 이전에
이미 죽어있었나요?
- Was he dead before the fall?
- He was dead before the impact.
피해자는 낙하 충격을 받기
전에 이미 죽어있었어
피해자는, 말하자면 정신이 나가 있었어
He drowned, so to speak.
열상으로 인한 출혈은
피해자가 낙하하면서
폐를 가득 채워버린 거군요
Blood from the lacerated artery
flooded his lungs on the flight down.
맞아
Exactly.
목 부근에서 이런 흔적을 발견했다네
I collected trace
from the neck wound.
검은색 가루 형태의 물질이야
A powdery black substance.
그리고 군데군데의 검은 얼룩들도 발견했지
And several black flecks.
피해자의 옷에서 모은 흔적들과
hopefully, analysis of these
will get us somewhere,
이 증거물들을 모으면
중요한 단서를 찾아낼 수 있길 바라야지
along with trace I collected
from the clothing.
자상을 낸 흔적으로
혹시 살인도구의 종류를 추정할 수 있나요?
The wound track help determine
the type of knife used?
좀 이상한 종류야
It was very odd.
칼자루 흔적도 없고
피해자의 피부 조직은
No hilt mark was evident,
and the tissue is jagged
표면이나 피하 모두
들쭉날쭉 찢어져 있어
at the surface as well
as within the wound.
살인도구가 칼 형태라면
Suggests the murder weapon
has an uneven blade,
고르지 못한 칼날 형태를 갖고 있겠군요
if it has a blade at all.
발견된 건 그뿐만이 아니야
And that wasn't my only discovery.
피해자의 입 안에서 발견된 것이야
This was in the victim's mouth.
신문지 뭉치로 추정된다네
It looks like
a page of newspaper.
살인자가 남긴 메세지일까요?
A message from the killer?
훔친 놈이 네놈인 줄 다 알아
두고봐라 내가 너 찾아낼꺼야 라고요?
"I know it's you,
I'm coming after you"?
이 핸드폰 당신 것 맞죠?
This is your phone, right?
음,, 그래요
Well... yeah.
협박 문자를 보낸 건 맞지만
I threatened him,
but I wanted to send
그저 훔친 놈이 누구였던간에
a clear message
to whoever it was
돌려달라는 의사를
표시하고 싶었을 뿐이예요
that stole it, that I wanted it back.
지난 새벽 1시에
어디에 있었지 캘빈?
Where were you last night, Calvin,
around 1:00 in the morning?
- 기억이 안 나요.
- 정말로?
- I can't remember.
- Really?
있잖아
You know,
uh...
이 감시카메라 영상이
어디에서 찍혔을까?
where this surveillance
footage was taken?
몰라요
No, I don't.
저게 무슨 엘레베이터인지 아시나요?
Do you know what elevator that is?
제가 묵던 호텔의 엘레베이터겠죠?
I'm guessing the elevator
in my hotel.
다시 생각해보는게 좋을걸.
That's a bad guess.
이건 913 빌딩의 나이트클럽으로
올라가는 엘레베이터에서
This is surveillance
footage of your mug
네가 소매치기를 당한 현장이 녹화된
heading up the elevator
to a nightclub
- 감시카메라 영상이지
- 새벽 1시경이었죠
- at Building 913.
- Around 1:00 a.m.
복수라도 하려고 했던건가요?
Were you looking for revenge?
아뇨 전..
No, I was...
데이트 상대를 찾고 있었어요
I was looking for a girl.
정말이예요
하루인가 이틀 전에 만난 여자였는데
All right? I met her a couple
nights ago, we hit it off,
클럽에서 만나기로 했었어요
we agreed to meet at the club.
그런데 핸드폰이 없어져서
졸지에 그 여자를 바람맞히게 되었죠
Only I didn't have my phone
to find out she stood me up.
그래요. 사실 화가 나긴 했어요
Okay?
Yeah, I was a little pissed,
그래서 그런 문자를 보낸 거예요
and I sent that message.
그런데 사람이 빡칠 수 있는 것도
불법은 아니잖아요?
But what law is there that says
a guy can't be a little peeved?
- 방금 "빡쳤다"라고 한거예요?
- "빡쳤다"라
- Did he just say "peeved"?
- Peeved.
그 가면 쓴 놈이 거리에서
자꾸 날 성가시게 하고 있었어요
That little masked man was
pestering me on the street
진짜 거슬렸다고요
and it really ticked me off.
그 놈이 성가시게 굴던 와중에
내 핸드폰을 훔친게 분명해요
It's got to be when
he lifted my phone.
그래서 어떻게 갚아줬나?
And what'd you do about it?
아무 것도 안했어요
Nothing.
그거 아나 캘빈?
You know what, Calvin?
네가 요즘 경찰들을 모르는가본데
You've got to tune into
a couple cop shows.
요즘에는 감시카메라라는게
These days, there's
surveillance cameras
뉴욕 곳곳에 깔려있단다
all over the city.
한번 구경해볼래?
Take a look at that.
안녕하셔요~?
Hey.
어이, 썩 꺼지지?
Hey, man, get back.
이봐요 뭐하는거예요?
Hey, hey, what are you doing?
가던 길 가시죠.
Just go.
말도 안돼
I can't believe this.
- 네가 봐도 놀랍지?
- 알았어요
Okay.
Yeah.
화가 나긴 했지만, 전 누구에게도
해를 끼치지 않았어요
I got mad, but I didn't kill nobody.
그 말엔 문제점이 하나 있어요 캘빈
There's only one problem, Calvin.
살인 피해자가 발견되었거든요
We have a dead guy.
그리고 당신이 엘레베이터로
그 클럽에 올라가는 영상이 남아있는데
And we have footage of you
going up that elevator,
문제는 거기서 내려오는 영상이 없더군요
- but not down.
- I took the stairs.
계단으로 내려갔어요
사람이 너무 많아서
There were too many people
줄이 전혀 줄질 않겠더라고요
waiting in line,
it would've taken forever.
94층이나 걸어서 내려가셨다?
You took the stairs 94 floors?
- 덕분에 술은 제대로 깼죠.
- 와우
- Burned off the booze, man.
- Wow.
운동 한번 제대로 했구만?
You're in shape, huh?
그 이야기를 증명해줄
증인이라도 있나?
Got anybody who can
back that story up?
이봐요
Look...
그냥 재미나게 놀려고
뉴욕에 온 것 뿐이예요
I came to New York
to have a good time.
전 내일 집에 돌아가요
Okay?
I leave tomorrow.
핸드폰도 없어져버렸고
I have no phone,
호텔은 진짜 구렸고,
뉴욕은 재미 하나도 없었어요
my hotel stinks, and
I didn't have any fun,
형사님들도 잘 아시겠다만
if you know what I mean.
게다가 방금 말했듯이
전 누구도 해하지 않았어요
Besides, like I said before,
I didn't kill nobody.
오히려 저는 명백한
피해자인 것 같은데요?
It's very clear to me
that I'm the victim here.
만나뵈려고 정말
오랫동안 노력했답니다
I've been trying to meet
you for a long time.
그 부분은 성공하신 것 같으네요
That part's accomplished.
무슨 말부터 해야 할 지 모르겠네요
I don't really even know
where to start.
자기 소개부터 하자면
Beginning, I guess.
저는 앨라배마 주의
터스칼루사에서 태어났어요
I was born in Tuscaloosa,
Alabama.
진짜?
Roll Tide!
나도 앨라배마 출신인데!
I'm from Alabama.
학부도 터스칼루사에서
마쳤는데 말이죠
I went to undergrad
in Tuscaloosa.
하지만 이런 제 학적도
다 조사해놨겠죠. 안 그래요?
But you know that, don't you?
- 우리 언제 만난 적 있는 사이인가요?
- 아뇨
- Did we meet before?
- No.
혹시 제 친구의 친구와 아는 사이인가요?
Do we have mutual friends?
아뇨
No.
전혀 아니예요
Not exactly.
8년 전, 저는 비후성 심근증이라는
Eight years ago, I was
diagnosed with a heart disease
심장병을 진단받았어요
called hypertrophic
cardiomyopathy.
그 병 때문에 심장의
혈액 공급이 불안했고
Um, it was very hard
for my heart to pump blood
심할 때면 죽을 듯이 아팠죠
and I was extremely sick.
지금은 건강해 보이는데요?
Well, you look very healthy now.
그건 제 증상이 3년만에
조기에 발견되었기 때문이예요
That's because three years after
my condition was discovered,
9월 13일에 심장 기증자로부터
심장을 이식받을 수 있었죠
on September 13, I was
given a donor heart.
수술은 정말 성공적이었어요
A very successful transplant.
건강한 기부자로부터
놀랍도록 꼭 맞는 심장을 이식받았죠
An incredible match,
and a healthy donor.
그게 당신이었어요?
That was you?
그래요
Yes.
당신이 그 심장을 이식받은 거예요?
You got her heart?
그래요
Yes.
그래서 그 기부자가 어느 분인지,
And I've been trying
to find out who she was,
어떻게 생긴 분일지
찾아다니고 있었어요
and what she was like.
오늘 미행하려는 의도는 없었어요
I didn't mean to follow you today.
사무실에 전화해보니 형사님이
안 계신다고 하더라고요
Your office said you weren't in,
그런데 우연히 형사님이
아파트에서 나오시는 걸 보고..
and you were coming out
of your apartment, I...
어떻게 다가가 말씀드려야 할 지
정말 모르겠더라고요
didn't exactly know
how to approach you.
제 행동들이 그저 형사님을
거슬리게 한 것 뿐인것 같네요
Just... trying to get up
the nerve, I guess.
그리고 이제는 제가
And now I'm hoping
I haven't made
형사님께 어마어마한
이기적 실수를 하지 않았길 바랄 뿐이예요
a big, giant selfish mistake.
제 동생의 심장을
이식받은 게 당신이었군요
You have my sister's heart.
와..
Whoa.
실례할게요
I'm sorry.
♪
여기 좀 덥지 않아요?
Is it hot in here?
에어컨이 작동을
안 하는것 같은데 말이죠
It's like the vent's not
blowing or something.
진짜 여기 좀 덥죠? 안 그래요?
I mean,
it's warm in here, right?
Mm-mm.
진짜로?
Really?
♪ I was towing the line
I was towing the line
♪ Looking for a little remedy
Looking for a little remedy
♪ Just a matter of time
Just a matter of time
♪ Till your hands
were healing me ♪
Till your hands
were healing me
♪ Yoo-hoo, you wanted to look
the devil right in the eye ♪
Yoo-hoo, you wanted to look
the devil right in the eye
♪ Yoo-hoo, you wanted to
Yoo-hoo, you wanted to
♪ Now I'm paying for it
with my life ♪
Now I'm paying for it
with my life
♪ Ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Now that I'm a hungry
and looking around ♪
Now that I'm a hungry
and looking around
♪ All this loving on the run
got me falling down ♪
All this loving on the run
got me falling down
♪ Climbing up the walls, boy,
you're coming down ♪
Climbing up the walls, boy,
you're coming down
♪ All this loving on the run
got me spinning round, round ♪
All this loving on the run
got me spinning round, round
♪ I was lining it up
I was lining it up
♪ We were out there
shooting the breeze ♪
We were out there
shooting the breeze
♪ Just a hat and a coat,
and a pocketful of dreams ♪
Just a hat and a coat,
and a pocketful of dreams
♪ Yoo-hoo, you wanted to look
the devil right in the eye ♪
Yoo-hoo, you wanted to look
the devil right in the eye
♪ Yoo-hoo, you wanted to
Yoo-hoo, you wanted to
♪ Now I'm paying for it
with my life ♪
Now I'm paying for it
with my life
♪ Ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
Ooh, ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Now that I'm a hungry
and looking around ♪
Now that I'm a hungry
and looking around
♪ All this loving on the run
got me falling down ♪
All this loving on the run
got me falling down
♪ Climbing up the walls, boy,
you're coming down ♪
Climbing up the walls, boy,
you're coming down
♪ All this loving on the run
got me spinning round, round. ♪
All this loving on the run
got me spinning round, round.
스팽글이었어!
Sequins.
♪
모든 층을 다 뒤져봐야 해요?
We gotta check every floor?
아냐, 전부 다 뒤지는 게 아니지
No, no.
We're not gonna
집에서 보고서도
안 읽어왔나보구만 애덤
check every floor.
If you'd do your homework
and read the reports, Adam,
시드 박사님의 부검 결과를 보면
Sid's autopsy suggests
that our vic fell
피해자는 6층~10층 정도
높이에서 떨어졌다는 걸 알 수 있어
somewhere between the
sixth and tenth floors.
- 부검 보고서 보고 말하시는게 아니잖아요?
- 맞아 안 읽어봤어
- You didn't read Sid's autopsy.
- Nah, I didn't read it.
반장님이 말씀해 주셨지
But Mac filled me in.
저도 다 알거든요?
That's how I do it.
가자고
Let's go.
여기가 1층인가보군
Looks like this
floor's the one.
유리에 피가 튀어 있고,
Blood on the glass.
여기 벽에도 튀어 있고,
On the wall here.
여기가 최초 범행 현장인 것 같아요
This could be our
primary crime scene.
피해자 키가 얼마만 했죠?
How tall's our vic?
155cm 정도
Five-11,
five-ten.
여기 혈흔이 없는
빈 공간이 있어요
There's a void here.
All right.
The arterial spray
동맥에서 나온 피의 흔적을 보니
살인범이 피해자를
마주보고 있던 것 같아요
suggests that the attacker
was facing him.
살인범은 피해자의 목을 그어냈고,
The attacker slices his throat,
피해자의 몸에서 튄 피가
살인범에게도 온통 튀었을 것이고
blood spatter goes
all over the killer,
두시문에도 튀었겠죠
on the back of the door.
혈흔이 빈 공간으로 봐서는
And the void suggests
that the attacker
살인범과 피해자는
키가 비슷할 가능성이 높아요
and the vic are roughly
the same height.
여기서 처음으로 피해자가 목을 찔렸고,
So the stabbing happened here.
핏자국을 따라가보면
The blood trail indicates
피해자가 이쪽으로 움직였겠지
that our victim moved
in this direction.
비틀거리며 구석까지 갔다가..
Then he staggered over
to the edge, and...
'으아아아~'
yeow...
맞아
I know.
그런데 피가 여기에 흥건히 남아 있어
I mean, but the blood pool
is right here.
여기서 엎어진 거야
So he dropped here.
구석까지는 걸어가지도 못한거야
Nowhere near the edge.
여기 흥건한 핏자국부터
문까지 이어지는
I've got partial footprints
발자국을 일부분 발견했어요
all the way to the door
from the blood pool.
피해자의 것이 아니었어요
They're not our vic's.
살인범의 신발 자국이겠죠.
So they got to be our killer's.
그런데 살인범이 왜 굳이
피해자를 찔러놓고 다시 돌아왔을까?
But why would the killer
come all the way back here
after he stabbed him?
피해자가 죽었나
확실히 확인해보고 싶었겠죠
He wanted to make
sure he's dead.
아니면
Or...
자신의 메세지를 남기고
싶었을 수도 있고
he wanted to leave a message.
피해자는 죽지 않기 위해
아둥바둥거렸어 애덤
The vic tried to stay alive, Adam.
여기까지 걸어 온거야
He got to his feet.
자기가 벼랑 끝까지 왔다는건
생각도 못했겠죠
He had no idea
he was close to the edge.
거기는 출구가 아니었는데
That's no way to go.
조 형사님!
Hey, Jo.
카페에 가방을 놓고 나오셨더라고요
You left your bag at the cafe.
고마워요
Thank you.
누가 리앤의 심장을 이식받았을까
매일같이 궁금해했었죠
I never stopped to think
about who got Leanne's heart.
제 동생을 차로 쳐버린
I was just so preoccupied
with my anger
가해자에 대한 분노로 가득해 있었고요
toward the guy that hit her.
음주운전자였어요, 비가 오는 날이었고요
Drunk driver.
It was raining.
그 때 전 버지니아에 있었죠
I was in Virginia at the time.
엄마한테 전화가 왔죠
Then Mama called.
조?
Jo?
엄마, 무슨 일이예요?
Mama, what is it?
조! 리앤이...
Jo, it's Leanne.
빨리 집에 오렴 아가야.
You got to come home, honey.
리앤은 아마 살아나지 못할 거야.
She's not gonna make it.
빨리 집에 오렴!
Jo, you got to come home.
리앤은 제가 집으로 운전해 가는
도중에 세상을 떴죠
She was gone before I even
made it out of my driveway.
그 때는 정말 슬픔으로 가득 차 있었고,
Wow, we were just
all so consumed with grief,
그 와중에 당신 가족들은
리앤의 심장이 딱 일치한다고 기뻐하고 있었죠
and all the while your family,
thrilled that Leanne was a match.
그 분이 제 목숨을 살려주신 거예요
She saved my life.
어떻게 절 찾은 거죠?
How did you find me?
제가 리앤의 누나라는 건 어떻게 알았죠?
How did you know I was her sister?
리앤이 기증자라는 건 또 어떻게 알았죠?
How did you know
Leanne was your donor?
저는 양쪽을 모두 이식받았거든요
I kind of put two and two together.
간호사 말로 기증자가
교통사고 피해를 당한 여성이라고 했었죠
A nurse said that
there was a car accident.
The heart came from a woman.
그 날을 기억해요
9월 13일
I knew the date, September 13.
무려 13일의 금요일이었지요
It was even a Friday.
그리고 그 심장이 얼마나 빨리
And, uh, I knew how quickly
they had to transport the heart
저에게 넘겨졌는지도 기억나요
from the donor to the recipient.
그래서 신문들을 보면서
교통 사고를 찾아본 거군요
So you searched the newspapers,
looking for accidents.
훨씬 전에 알아챈 거 아니었나요?
You must have known before now.
그랬죠
I did.
그런데 한 가정의 사랑받는 딸을
잃어버린 유가족들에게 가서
How do you walk up to
someone and say to them
that you have the heart
of someone they lost,
심장을 기증해줘서 고맙다고
대뜸 인사할 수는 없는 법이잖아요
someone they loved?
- 직업이 뭐예요?
- 교수예요.
- What do you do, Grant?
- I'm a professor.
멤피스 대학에 들어가서
Joined the faculty
at Memphis University.
물리를 가르치는 사람이예요
I teach physics.
기혼이예요?
Are you married?
아뇨
No.
약혼은 한 번 했는데
Got engaged once.
막상 결혼식 날이 오니
겁을 먹어서 도망가버렸죠
I got cold feet.
리앤도 결혼을 하지 않았죠
Leanne never married.
남자는 끝내 결혼식장인
교회에도 나타나지 않았죠
Never even made it
to the church.
아빠는 돈을 다 날려버렸다고
매우 화를 내셨죠
Daddy was so mad;
he'd spent all his money.
결혼 안 하길 잘 한거예요
그런 겁쟁이랑 결혼할 필요 없죠
She was right.
That guy was a creep.
당신은 좋은 남자인가요?
Are you a good man, Grant?
그렇다고 봐요
I think so.
심장 이식이 끝나고
처음 정신이 들었을 때
When you woke up
from the transplant surgery,
제일 먼저 기억나는 것은 무엇이었나요?
what was the first thing
that you remember?
밝고 따뜻한 햇살이요
A bright warm light.
그리고 한 여자의 웃는 얼굴이요
And then a woman's smiling face.
어머니셨죠?
Your mama.
아뇨
No.
제가 모르는 여성의 얼굴이었어요
It was a face I didn't know,
그리고 지금 형사님을 보고 있자니
그 여성은 형사님의 동생분이었던 것 같아요
and now that I see you, I
think it was your sister.
와..
Wow.
자네 괜찮나?
Hey, are you okay?
- 저요?
- 그래, 자네
- Who, me?
- Yeah, you.
네, 전 괜찮아요
왜요?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Why?
자네 약간 좀..
You looked a little, um...
- 혼란스러워보인다고요?
- 그런 말을 하려고 했던 건 아닌데만..
- Perplexed.
- Well, that's not the word
I was going to use, but...
아, 시드 박사님이 피해자의
입 안에서 찾아낸 종이뭉치는
Well, the crumpled paper
that Sid found
in the victim's mouth,
'Chelsea Voice 주간지'였어요
it came from the
Chelsea Voice Weekly.
일단 알아낸 건 여기까지지만,
So that's all I've got,
uh, but I'm hoping
그것과 피해자와의 연결고리를
찾아내려고 노력하고 있어요
to make a connection
to our victim,
that can lead us to our killer.
참, 저는 여기 서서
한가롭게 반장님이랑
So I probably
shouldn't be standing
수다나 떨어서는 안되는 거겠죠
그런 거죠?
around here chatting with you,
you know what I mean?
-그렇죠?
-도와 줄 일이라도 있나?
Okay.
You need help?
아뇨 아뇨
No. No.
아뇨..
No.
이봐 자네
나에게 10달러 빚진 거 있지?
Hey, you owe me ten bucks.
방금 린지를 봤다네
I just saw Lindsay.
아니, 아무 말도 하지 않더군
No, she didn't say anything.
내 생각이 맞은 것 같아
I just know I'm right.
내가 누군데
I know I am.
아냐 크리스틴
No, Christine,
지금 린지한테 물어보지는 않을 거야
I'm not going to come
right out and ask her.
무슨 증거라고?
What kind of proof?
알았어
All right.
증거를 갖다주지
I'll get you proof.
내일 저녁 약속은
유효한 거지?
We still on for dinner
tomorrow night?
좋아
Great.
나도 사랑해
I love you, too.
끊을게
Bye.
혹시 마약이라도 만드는 중인가?
You cooking something or should I say
아니면 내가 타는 냄새를 잘못 맡은 건가?
burning something in here, Sheldon?
탄소와 폴리머와 지방산과
치클 고무를 섞으면 어떻게 될까요?
What do you get if you
combine carbon, polymer,
탄소와 폴리머와 지방산과
치클 고무를 섞으면 어떻게 될까요?
(치클 고무 : 껌의 원료)
fatty acids and chicle?
어디 보자
Let's see.
폴리머는 플라스틱 종류이고
Polymer is some kind of plastic.
지방산은 어떤 것이든 될 수 있으니
Fatty acids
could be almost anything,
일단 여기서 나는 냄새로 볼 때
but based on the smell in here,
I'm guessing it's a kind of food.
음식 종류일 것 같군
탄소는 불과 결합되는 물질이고
The carbon is associated with fire,
치클 고무는 껌이지
chicle is gum.
자네가 물어본 것만 갖고 맞추자면
We're gonna be here all day
정답을 죽었다 깨어나도 못 맞출 것 같군
if I try guessing exactly
where you're headed here.
정답은 살인도구예요
It's our murder weapon.
플라스틱, 지방산, 껌으로?
Plastic, fatty acids, and gum?
위험성이라고는
전혀 느낄 수 없는 것들인데?
That doesn't sound
too dangerous.
말씀드린 것들은 모두
Those were all components
that were detected
시드 박사님이 상처 부위에서
찾아낸 것들이예요
in the trace Sid collected
from the victim's stab wound.
칼에서 묻은 흔적이라
Trace left by the knife.
직접 만든 칼인가보군
Which would suggest
the knife was man-made.
그렇죠. 살인도구를 만드는 데에 쓰인
준비물은 AA배터리와
Mm-hmm, and it was created
by first using an AA battery
껌 포장지예요
and a foil gum wrapper.
스파크를 튀게 만들지
The creation of a spark.
껌 포장지 때문에
치클 고무가 발견된 것일 테고
Ah, the gum wrapper
was the source of our chicle.
껌 포장지의 알루미늄 호일을
You attach the foil side
배터리의 +극과 -극에 동시에
to the battery's positive
and negative charge
붙여버린다면,
at the same time,
스파크가 튀어 불이 나는 거야
you get a spark
that starts a fire.
정확해요
Exactly.
이제 의문점은
왜 이런 식으로 불을 붙였냐는 것이지
The question is
why would someone need
이제 의문점은
왜 이런 식으로 불을 붙였냐는 것이지
to start a fire that way?
보통 불을 붙이려고 한다면
Well, most likely someone
누구라도 쉽게 성냥이나
라이터를 사서 불을 붙이겠지만
who didn't have access
to matches or a lighter.
그럴 수 없는 사람이 있겠죠?
Both easily accessible unless...
감옥 수감자로군
You're in a prison cell.
맞습니다.
Yeah.
살인도구는 개인이
직접 만든 것이었군
The murder weapon
was a handmade shank.
그리고 그 살인도구의
제조법을 알아낸 것 같아요.
And I believe I know the recipe.
콘칩 과자는 지방산을 의미하고,
A pile of corn chips
represents the fatty acids.
그걸로 스파크를 튀게 만들고,
Start a spark,
냅킨이나 휴지로
불을 점화시킨다면
ignite a napkin
or toilet paper.
과자에 있는 기름 성분이
연료 역할을 할 수 있겠지
The oils in the chip serve
as a slow burning fuel source.
탄소 성분은 불에 타고 남은 재였어
The burn is the carbon.
상처 주변에 검은색 가루 비슷한
물질이 남아 있었죠
The black soot trace found
in the wound.
폴리머가 플라스틱이었어
Polymer is a plastic.
1회용 포크나 칫솔로
쉽게 쓸 수 있었을 거예요
A plastic fork or toothbrush.
이번 범행에서 살인범은
일회용 커피잔을 사용했지요
In our case, the killer used
a coffee cup to-go lid.
시드 박사님이 상처 주변에서
찾아낸 검은 얼룩이로군
The black flecks Sid found
in the wound.
열로 형상을 만들어내면
Molded over heat
칼날의 형태가 만들어지죠
in the shape of the blade.
그걸 바로 물에 담그면,
Submerge it in water,
순간적으로 매우 단단해지지
it instantly hardens.
그걸 반복적으로 갈아내면,
File it down,
repeat the process
하나의 살인도구가 완성되는 것이군
and you have a murder weapon.
이 재료들은 모두 감옥 수감자들도
쉽게 구할수 있는 것들이예요
All of these are items that
are accessible to inmates.
살인범은 전과자임이 분명해요
Our killer is an ex-con.
그리고 복수를 할 작정이었어
And hell-bent on revenge.
반장님 포기하세요
Mac, I give up.
제가 항복할게요
I surrender.
더 이상 기댈 곳도 없어요
I have nowhere else to turn.
이번엔 대니가 뭘 했는가?
What did Danny do now?
그게 아니라 업무 때문에 그래요
No, this time it's work.
피해자의 입 안에서 발견된
The crumpled piece of paper
that Sid found
신문지 뭉치 말이예요
in our victim's mouth...
1면이군.
Front page.
"Chelsea Voice 주간지"
Chelsea Voice Weekly.
2011년 2월 6일이라
February 6, 2011.
맞아요, 이제 중요한 건
여기에 어떤 중요한 단서가 숨어 있냐는 것이죠
Right, so the big question is
what's the significance, right?
해당 날짜의 주간지에는
예술과 관련된 지면이 있었고,
There's an article about art.
음악 축제에 대한 내용도 있었고,
There's an article
about a music festival,
발렌타인 데이 관련 내용도 있었는데
a Valentine's Day benefit.
피해자와 연결지을만한
내용은 전혀 없었어요
None of it has anything
to do with our victim.
물론 아직도 피해자가
신원미상이라,
Of course, he's still
a John Doe, so I could be
사실 그 신문 뭉치를 보고 있어도
알 수 있는 게 전혀 없더라고요
staring at the answer
and I wouldn't know it.
문제가 눈 앞에 있는데
답을 모르겠네요
Oh, we were staring at
it and didn't even know it.
내가 하려던 말이었는데!
That's exactly what I just said.
피해자의 자켓 속주머니에서 나온
도난 핸드폰들을
We assumed the phones
관광객들이 도난당한
핸드폰일 거라고 가정해봤어요
inside the hidden pocket
of the suit jacket
관광객들이 도난당한
핸드폰일 거라고 가정해봤어요
were taken from tourists.
하나의 예외를 빼고 전부 다
관광객의 도난 핸드폰이었죠
All of them were claimed
except for one.
그래서 이동통신 회사에 전화를 해서
그 예외적인 핸드폰 주인을 알아냈어요
So I called the phone company,
and I got a name.
알렉스 헨리, 22세,
퀸즈의 아스토리아에 사는 사람이예요
Alex Henley, 22,
from Astoria, Queens.
그러자 제 뇌리를 스치는 게 있었죠
And then it dawned on me.
그건 도난 핸드폰이 아니었군
The phone wasn't stolen.
피해자의 것이었어
It belongs to our vic.
좋아요
Okay, there you go.
미래의 좋은 핸드폰요금
절약 방법을 찾아낸 것 같네요
I sense a promotion
in the near future.
그래서 우리 신원미상 피해자는
알렉스 헨리라는 사람이군요
So Alex Henley is our John Doe.
그럼 이 주간지 1면에서
So let's see if he connects
to anything
알렉스 헨리와 연결지을 만한 게
있나 찾아보죠
on the front page of the paper.
연관되는 게 없네요
No connection.
기사 내용이 아니라
1면에 적힌 그 날짜와 상관이 있는게 아닐까?
Maybe it's not the stories
but the date on that front page.
저 삑 소리 진짜 싫으네요
I hate that sound.
또 맞는게 없어요
No match.
잠깐만, 이게 피해자와
연결고리가 있는게 아니라면
Wait a minute, if the
connection isn't to our victim,
살인범과의 연결고리가
있을 지도 몰라
it's got to be to our killer.
호크스가 밝혀내기로
살인무기는 전과자가 만들어낸
Hawkes determined that the
murder weapon was a shank,
인조 칼자루 형태였어
making our killer an ex-con.
다시 한 번 2011년 2월 6일의
So connect February 6, 2011,
모든 법 판결이나 관련 문서들과
교차 검색해봐봐
to any legal actions,
dockets, or convictions.
와, 엄청난데요?
Whoa, that's a huge file.
그런데요, 남자가 스팽글을 차나요?
Hey, um, do men wear sequins?
제 말이,
I mean,
캬바레나 라스베가스에서야
그럴 만한 사람이 있겠지만요
I know they do
in cabarets and Vegas.
좋아요, 어쨌든 제 말은
Okay, well, my point is
호크스 박사 말로
시드 박사님이 피해자의 옷에서
Hawkes said that
Sid found sequins
스팽글 조각을 발견했다고 했고,
on the the vic's suit,
이게 아마 살인범이 남겨놓은
흔적일 지도 몰라요
so it could be transfer
from our killer.
그건 괴담에 나오는 얘기인데요?
That's part of the legend.
웬트워스는 태양 알레르기가 있어서
Wentworth was allergic to sun,
밖에 잘 나가지 않았죠
so he rarely went out, right,
and he always kept
펜트하우스에 칩거하면서
옷으로 자기 몸을 꽁꽁 싸매고 있었고요
the drapes in his
penthouse closed.
그래서 웬트워스는 그를 찾아오는
모든 여성 방문객으로 하여금
So he made this request
that all his female visitors
빛을 가져오게 하기 위해
스팽글 옷을 입고 오도록 해놨다죠
wear sequins to bring in the light.
그 클럽은 그 괴담의
내용을 기리기 위해
The club still offers free entry
스팽글 옷을 입고 들어오는 여자들은
무료 입장을 시켜준다고 하네요
to any women who still
honor that request.
좋아, 그럼 그런 여성으로
검색 범위를 한정해보지
Okay, let's limit
the search to women.
운이 좋다면 그 중에
살인범이 있겠네요
Hopefully one of them
will be our perp.
린지, 강도 현장을
다시 검토해봐
Linds, go back a set
of mug shots.
알았어.
Okay.
여기 금발 여자가 있네요
This girl right here, this blonde.
지난 새벽 1시에
어디에 있었지 캘빈?
Where were you last night,
Calvin, around 1:00 in the morning?
기억이 안 나요
I can't remember.
정말로?
Really?
있잖아..
You know, uh...
이건 사건 당일날 새벽 1시 쯤
This is surveillance footage
from the elevator
사건 현장의 엘레베이터에서 찍힌
at the crime scene the
night of the murder,
감시카메라 영상이예요
roughly around 1:00 a.m.,
여기 이 여자도
감시카메라 영상에 보이고 있죠
and this girl right here
is also in this footage.
스팽글 스카프를 차고 있네요?
She's wearing a sequined scarf.
메이시 설리번,
2011년 2월 6일 체포
Macy Sullivan,
arrested February 6, 2011.
장물에 대한 소지 혐의
Criminal possession
of stolen property,
2급 범죄 판결
second degree.
2011년 2월 6일
February 6, 2011,
이게 그 연결고리예요
이 여자가 체포된 날이요!
that's the connection,
the day she was arrested.
2년형을 선고받았는데
2주 전에 출소했어요
She did a two year sentence
and got out two weeks ago.
그래, 이 여자의 신원을 확보했어
Okay, we have her in the building,
but we don't have her near the body.
하지만 아직 잡지 못한 상태이지
스팽글 조각이 옮겨붙는 것 정도야
Transfer of the sequin
어디에서나 누구에게든
쉽게 있을 수 있는 일이지
could have happened
anywhere from anyone.
저 여자는 피해자와 키가 비슷해요
Well, she's roughly
the same height as the vic.
- 딱 맞는다고요!
- 심증일 뿐이야
- I mean, it fits.
- Circumstantial.
알렉스 헨리를 살해하는 데에
We need a connector
to Alex Henley's murder
쓰인 살인 무기가
by putting her on that landing
저 여자의 소유라는 것을 확인시켜줄
연결고리가 필요해
with the murder
weapon in her hand.
애덤이 살인 현장에서 발견한
부분 발자국들은
The partial footprints Adam
photographed at the scene
상당히 작게 나왔어요
여성의 것일 수 있어요
are small...
could be a woman.
그런걸 지방검사에게
증거로 제출할 수는 없다네
Can't take it to the D.A.
혹시 현장에 미상 인물의
피가 있었나?
Any unknown blood
at the scene?
전부 피해자의 것이었어요
All belonged to our vic.
문 손잡이랑 유리 하나 하나
다 조사해봤는데 지문도 없어요
We dusted the door handles
and the glass. No prints.
플랙과 로바토 형사가
메이시 설리번의 주소를
Flack and Lovato got an
address on Macy Sullivan
가석방 담당자로부터 확보했어요
지금 출동하는 중이고요
from her parole officer.
They're headed there now.
가석방 담당자는 최근
거취 보고를 받지 못했다고 해요
P.O. said she didn't
check in today.
She's running.
Get her picture out.
도주 중일거야
사진을 뽑아내게
모든 공항과,
Have all the airports,
버스터미널, 렌터카 업체에게
협조를 구해서
bus stations, car rental
companies check
지난 18시간 내에 메이시 설리번을
목격한 적이 있나 확인해보도록 해
their surveillance
for the past 18 hours.
외부로 이탈했다는 게 확인되면
가석방 의무 위반으로 체포하라고 하게
If he finds her, have Flack pick
her up for parole violation.
그동안 우리는..
In the meantime...
메이시 설리번이 살인범이라는
증거를 찾아내야 하네
we got to prove that
Macy Sullivan's our killer.
메이시 설리번! 뉴욕 경찰이다!
Macy Sullivan! NYPD!
떠난지 오래로군
She's long gone.
급하게 떠났어
She left in a hurry, too.
실험실에 갖다주면 좋아하겠군
The guys at the lab might like this.
우리가 사람을
잘못 쫓고 있는 것 같아요.
I think we're looking
for the wrong person.
무슨 말이야?
What do you mean?
현재 이 여자는 우리가 생각했던 것과
전혀 다르게 생겼을 거예요
I mean she doesn't look like
what we think she looks like.
이 여자는 염색을 했어요
금발도 아니고 이제 단발머리가 됐겠죠
She's no longer a blonde.
And she cut her hair.
메이시 설리번에 대한
전국 지명 수배를 요청한다
I need an APB out on
a Macy Sullivan.
흑갈색 머리의 단발 여성이다
Brunette, short hair.
모든 대원들에게 알린다:
All units be advised:
용의자로 추정되는 여성 발견,
female matching description,
롱아일랜드 버스터미널에서
버스를 기다리고 있는 것으로 추정됨.
possible sighting
Long Island city bus terminal.
주의를 끌지 않게
사이렌이나 헤드라이트를 키지 말고 출동할 것
Proceed, no lights, no sirens.
이봐요!
Hey!
로바토!
Lovato.
발견했어요!
I see her.
뉴욕 경찰이다! 손 들어!
NYPD, freeze!
저리 비켜!
Out of my way!
♪
이걸 챙겨갔어야 하지 않나?
Should've taken it with you.
급하게 가던 중이어서요
I was in a hurry.
스카프에서 알렉스 헨리의
혈흔을 발견했다네
Found Alex Henley's
blood on the scarf.
네 방에서 발견된 스카프였지
스팽글 조각이 일부 없어졌더군
Found the scarf in your room.
There was a missing sequin.
그 조각들은
피해자의 몸에서 발견되었고
Found that on Henley's body.
왜 그 자를 죽인 건가?
Why'd you kill him?
네가 여기 정말 와 줬다니
놀라워 메이시
Can't believe you're here, Macy.
이 순간을 기다려 왔어
I've been waiting for
this moment a long time.
결국 널 다시 만나게 되다니
Finally seeing you again.
정말?
Really?
내가 유죄 판결을 받은 날 이후로
얼마나 고대해온 날인데!
It's all I've thought about
since the day I was convicted.
당신은 복수를 한 거야
You were after revenge.
나는 내가 저지르지도 않은
범죄로 유죄 판결을 받았어요
Hey, I was put away for crimes
that I did not commit.
저에겐 죄가 없노라고
그렇게 얘기를 해도 소용이 없었죠
No matter how many times I told them
I was innocent, it didn't matter.
알렉스 헨리조차도 믿어주지 않았죠
Especially not to Alex Henley.
그 놈을 믿었는데..
I trusted him.
그 놈은 제 남자친구여서
I guess I thought
I could trust him
제가 그렇게 믿었던 걸지도 몰라요
because he was my boyfriend.
같이 살던 아파트 옷장에서
가방을 하나 발견했어요
I found the bag in the
closet in our apartment.
그 안을 들여다보고는 알렉스를 불러
그동안 무슨 일을 했던거냐고 물어봤죠
I looked inside, called Alex,
and did what he told me to.
알렉스, 그래서 어떻게 하라는 거야?
Alex, what do you want
me to do with it?
그냥 나한테 가져와
Just bring the bag to me.
그런데 이 가방이 왜
우리 아파트에 있는거냐고?
But why is it in
our apartment?
메이시, 진정해
Macy, calm down.
여기에 일단 최대한
빨리 오도록 해
Just get here as
fast as you can.
당신 사건 기록을 읽어보니
검사와 협상을 할 여지가 있었더군
I read your case file, and
you could've made a deal.
전 무죄예요
I was innocent.
제가 왜 거래를 해야 하죠?
What would I need to make a deal?
메이시 당신은 장물 소지로
체포된 상태였어
You were in possession
of stolen property, Macy.
당신이랑 같이 사진을 찍고난 뒤
There was a woman that
identified you as someone
목걸이가 사라져버린 도난 피해 여성이 있었지
she took a picture with,
그 사진 속 여성은 당신으로 확인되었어
and then discovered her
necklace was gone.
당신이랑 알렉스는
같이 사기를 치던 한 패였던거야
It's the scam that
you and Alex played.
그 놈이 계속 해왔던 그 짓 말야
The one he continued to play.
나는 도둑이 아니예요!
I was not the thief, okay?
도둑놈은 오직 알렉스 혼자예요
It was Alex.
It was only Alex.
그 놈이 사람들로부터
물건을 훔친다고는 생각도 못 했어요
I didn't know that he was
stealing from people.
그저 사람들과 같이 사진을 찍어주면서
돈을 버는 줄로만 알았죠
I thought we were just taking
pictures and making money.
그 놈이 소매치기를 하고 있을 거라고는
But I never for one second
considered
단 한 순간도 생각해본 적이 없어요.
that he was the one stealing.
♪
그 가방을 제가 발견하자
When I found the bag,
he told me that
그 놈은 친구 것을
맡아주고 있는 거라고 변명했고
저는 그 말을 믿어줬죠
he was holding it for a friend,
and I believed him.
하지만 그 친구라는 건 거짓말이었지?
But there was no friend.
그랬죠
No.
그래서...
So...
감옥에 들어가
복수의 계획을 짰죠
I sat in prison and
came up with my plan.
그 놈은 당해도 쌌죠
He was gonna pay.
당신이 두 번이나 콩밥을
먹어도 될 만한 가치가 있는 일인가?
Was it all worth going
back to prison, Macy?
그 놈이 나에게 저지른 걸
갚아줬을 뿐이예요
I got him back
for what he did to me.
당연히 가치가 있는 일이죠
So, yeah, it was worth it.
죄송해요, 본의 아니게
형사님의 휴일을 방해했네요
Hey, I'm sorry I interrupted
your plans for your day off.
아니예요, 정말 예기치 않았던
즐거운 시간이었어요 그랜트
Oh, it was an unexpected
pleasure, Grant, really.
제 여동생을 보는 것 같았어요
Something my sister
would have done.
제 여동생도 늘 예측할 수 없이
이리 튀고 저리 튀곤 했고
She was so spontaneous
and unpredictable.
제 멋대로였지만 사랑스런 동생이었죠
And irresponsible, but very loving.
당신을 안 지 얼마 되지는 않았지만
I haven't know you very long,
제 여동생의 심장을 갖고 있는
사람이라고 확신할 수 있겠네요
but if feels right that
you have her heart.
왜 이렇게 심장 기증자를
찾는 일에 열심이신가요?
Why was this so
important to you?
이식을 받아야 할 환자들은
저처럼 행운이 넘치질 못하죠
Transplant patients aren't
always as lucky as I was.
그레서 저는 숨쉬는 순간
하나 하나를 소중히 여겨요
Every breath that I take,
I cherish.
여전히 누군가가 목숨을 바쳐
It's still hard knowing
that someone had
제게 새 생명을 주었다는 사실이
부담스럽고요
to die so I could live.
그래서 누군가에게는 꼭
감사의 표시를 하고 싶었어요
And I wanted to say thank you...
to somebody.
아녜요.
You're welcome.
제가..
I-I have a...
제가 정말 말도 안 되는
부탁을 드리고 싶은데요
I have the craziest request.
당신 심장 소리를
들어봐도 되나요?
Can I listen to your heart?
심장 박동 소리요
Hear it beat?
그럼요
Absolutely.
오..
Oh.
정말 세네요
It's strong.
그리고 아름다워요
Oh, it's beautiful.
고마워요
Thank you.
별 일 아녜요
You bet.
좋아, 이제 끝난거지?
와, 와, 와, 저기 지나간다
Okay, so, we're good.
Whoa, guys, guys, here she goes.
- 뭐라고?
- 저기 린지가 간다고.
- What?
- Here she goes.
아니지! 지금 와서
바꾸는 게 어디 있어!
No, no, this is
no time for questions.
- 돈까지 걸어놨는데!
- 신난다
- I got money on the line.
- Exciting.
- 자네 여기서 뭐 하고 있는건가?
- 안녕하세요!
- Hey, what are you doing here?
- Hey, guys.
오늘 쉬는 날 아니었나?
I thought this was your day off.
그랬죠!
최고의 휴일을 보냈죠
It was.
It was terrific.
여기서 뭣들 하는거야?
What are you all doing?
시드 박사님이 린지가
말을 할거라고 하셔서요 자꾸
Sid thinks she's
about to tell him.
누가 누구한테 뭘 말한다고?
Oh, yeah.
Who's she? Tell who what?
아! 지금 시작된다! 시작돼요!
Oh, here we go.
Here we go.
- 안녕!
- 안녕! 나갈 준비 됐어?
- Hey.
- Hey. You ready to hit the road?
대니, 나 임신했어
Danny, I'm pregnant.
뭐?
What?
지금 농담하는 거 아니지?
Are you being serious
with me right now?
응, 오늘 두 번이나 테스트해봤어
Yes. I've thrown up twice today.
임신 검사기만 네 번을 써 봤는데
모두 임신했다고 떴어
I've taken four pregnancy tests,
and they were all positive.
- 진짜? 진짜?
- 응
- Really? Really?
- Yeah.
시작된다
There we go.
좋아뵈네요
Look-Looking good.
그럴 리가
No.
맞아요
Yes.
- 박사님!
- 안돼 안돼 안돼
- Sid...
- No, no, no.
조금만 기다려봐
Wait, wait-wait
for it.
우리 딸 루시가 누나가 될거야!
Lucy's gonna be a big sister.
우리 아기 생겼다!
We're having a baby!
오..
Aw...
- 세상에나!
- 이제 돈 내시지 제군들.
- Oh, my God.
- Pay up, gentlemen.
저희 임신했어요 반장님
We're having a baby, Mac.
축하하네
Congratulations.
고맙네그려
Thank you very much.
여기요.
There you go.
- 그래 이거지
- 그렇네요
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Yeah.
어디 있지?
Where is it?
수표로 드려도 되나요?
You take checks?
린지가 임신했어!
She's pregnant.
내가 하루 휴일을 쓴 동안에
임신 소식이라니!
I'm gone one day
and she's pregnant.
임신 소식 공개가
너무 이른 것 같지 않아?
Don't you think it's a little
early to be telling everybody?
안 그래도 벌써 알고 있었을걸?
Uh, I think they already know.
- 축하해요!
- 뭐야 내기도 한거였어?
Congratulations.
Was there a bet?
물론이고말고!
Uh, yeah.
한글자막 아방가르드
http://avantgarde.egloos.com/
재배포 허용. 수정은 제작자와 협의 하에